Editor: Fred Albino
Updated Date: 2/22/2020

Notes from Git Tutorial Class on Udemy

Git Status Comparisons

Local
Working Directory - where you can make changes independently without any affect on Git.
Staging Area - where you can add your files to so when they're commited, the commit of all files in this Area is done as one atomic unit.
Repository (.git folder) - Once commited, the files will be added here but not yet into your Remote Repo.

Remote
Remote Repository - once you commit and push your changes, then they will be displayed as part of the final code in the Remote Repository.

Starting with a Fresh Project.
git init "project name" - will create a folder with a .git subfolder.

Adding Git to an Existing Project 
git init - without specifying a project name, Git will use the current folder to track the files.

Starting on Github by Joining an Existing Project
git clone - will copy the remote repo into the current directory being used and add a .git folder along with an Origin that points back to the Remote Repo.



To find out where your git Repository root is type the following command:
git rev-parse --show-toplevel 

If you don't want this folder to be a git folder, then delete the .git folder container within it.
Run the following command to see all folder: ls -a
Run the following command to delete the git folder: rm -r -force .git
